Finding Aid for John Lesinski papers, 1930s-1964
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Congressional Files, 1951-1964
  - Speeches, Statements and News Releases
    - Foreign Trade Interests in Michigan, July 1956 (Box 8)
    - Report from Washington, July 1959 (Box 8)
    - Metro Monster, July 1959 (Box 8)
    - Report from Washington, October 1959 (Box 8)
    - Census and Government Statistics, October 28, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Study of Statistical Activities in Government, October 29, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Statement before federal employees, November 14, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Subcommittee on Census and Government Statistics, December 6, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Congressional Record Remarks, 1959-1960 (Box 8)
    - Restore Benefits of 1958 Lesinski Act Preserving Basic Compensation in Downgrading Actions, February 17, 1960 (Box 8)
    - Office Automation and Employees, February 24, 1960 (Box 8)
    - Federal Employees and costs for data compilation activities, March 3, 1960 (Box 8)
    - Final Plans for 1960 Census, March 18, 1960 (Box 8)
    - Office Automation and Employee Job Security, April 13, 1960 (Box 8)
    - Endorsement of candidate by 16th District Democratic Organization, April 22, 1960 (Box 8)
    - Report from Washington, 1960 (Box 8)
    - House Resolution statement, May 5, 1960 (Box 8)
    - Statement, May 31, 1960 (Box 8)
    - Teamsters Union Election, June 9, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Reduction of Reporting Burden on Truck and Bus Operators, June 28, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Paderewski Commemorative Stamp, June 11, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Favorable action on Lesinski bills, June 21, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Comparative Salary advantages of military to civilian personnel, June 28, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Urban Blight, July 1, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Report on 86th Congress, July 1960 (Box 9)
    - Subcommittee on Census, July 31, 1960 (Box 9)
    - City Officials on more frequent Census taking, August 29, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Data Processing Equipment in Federal Government, September 14, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Report from Washington, October 1960 (Box 9)
    - Protests Revoking ban on communist speakers at Wayne State University, October 6, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Lesinski Act, October 27, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Eisenhower's Directive to Curtail Overseas Spending, November 17, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Liberation of Armenia, November 30, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Reappointment to Post Office and Civil Service Committee, 1961 (Box 9)
    - Report to Washington, January 1961 (Box 9)
    - Report to Washington, February 1961 (Box 9)
    - Transportation Census, March 1, 1961 (Box 9)
    - Reduction in federal reports for motor carriers, March 12, 1961 (Box 9)
    - Salary protection for postal service employees, March 16, 1961 (Box 9)
    - Salary protection, March 20, 1961 (Box 9)
    - Subcommittee on Census, March 28, 1961 (Box 9)
    - Results of closed meeting on 1960 census, May 5, 1961 (Box 9)
    - Postal Workers as Census Takers, May 25, 1961 (Box 9)
    - Public Works Appropriations, June 13, 1961 (Box 9)
    - Opposition to Postal Rates Increase, June 18, 1961 (Box 9)
    - Report from Washington, October 1961 (Box 9)
    - Census and Transportation, 1961 (Box 9)
    - National Census of Transportation, July 18-19, 1961 (Box 9)
    - Radio and TV scripts, 1961 (Box 9)
    - Congressional Record Remarks, 1961 (Box 9)
    - Trenton Channel, January 1962 (Box 9)
    - Detroit Arsenal, February 6, 1962 (Box 9)
    - Polish Legion, February 7, 1962 (Box 9)
    - Letter to Kennedy, February 7, 1962 (Box 9)
    - Henry Ford Stamp, July 18, 1962 (Box 9)
    - Letter to President Kennedy on Tax Cut, August 3, 1962 (Box 9)
    - Purchasing of Defense Material, July 19, 1962 (Box 9)
    - Letter to President Kennedy on Henry Ford Stamp, July 13, 1962 (Box 9)
    - Food and Drug, June 20, 1962 (Box 9)
    - Rouge River Project, May 15, 1962 (Box 9)
    - Current Projects, May 1962 (Box 9)
    - Detroit Arsenal, April 4, 1962 (Box 9)
    - Income Tax Reduction, May 1962 (Box 9)
    - Federal Aid to Education, May 1962 (Box 9)
    - Henry Ford Stamp, June 27, 1963 (Box 9)
    - HR 8884 News Release, October 22, 1963 (Box 9)
    - Memorial Tablet, August 21, 1964 (Box 9)
    - Civil Rights, 1964 (Box 9)
    - Civil Rights Employment, May 12, 1964 (Box 9)
    - Religion and Civil Rights, April 23, 1964 (Box 9)
    - Ford Motor Plant, July 9, 1964 (Box 9)
    - NAACP, July 8, 1964 (Box 9)
  - Campaign Materials
    The Campaign materials subseries includes posters, statements, newsletters, and some correspondence primarily focused on the 1964 campaign. Other materials include voting records, nominating petitions, and local issues related to the campaign.
    - 18th District Democratic Organization, 1955-1961 (Box 9)
    - State Central Committee, 1954-1956 (Box 9)
    - Election Returns, 1950-1962 (Box 9)
    - Election miscellaneous, 1956 (Box 9)
    - Election miscellaneous, 1958 (Box 9)
    - Election miscellaneous, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Election miscellaneous, 1962 (Box 9)
    - Election, 1964
      - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
      - Biography (for campaign), 1964 (Box 9)
      - Voting Records Lesinski and Dingell, 1964 (Box 9)
      - Campaign News Release, Labor, 1964 (Box 9)
      - Announcement for Candidacy, 1964 (Box 9)
      - Filing for Petition, 1964 (Box 9)
      - Newsletter, 1964 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous (various election campaigns) (Box 10)
  - Topical:, 1951-1964
    The Topical files are further divided into General and Michigan topics.
    - General
      The general files are arranged in alphabetical order by topic. These materials include correspondence, reports, and government documents. Major subject areas include civil rights, labor, the post office, and foreign policy. Particularly valuable are the civil rights and communism files. The files under the heading "nationalities" primarily focuses on Lesinski's special interest in eastern bloc countries. They are organized alphabetically by country.
      - Agriculture General Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 11)
      - Agriculture Bulletins, 1964 (Box 11)
      - Anti-Trust, 1958 (Box 11)
      - Appropriations, 1955-1958 (Box 11)
      - Area Redevelopment, 1961-1962 (Box 11)
      - Automotive Industry, 1958-1961 (Box 11)
      - Aviation, 1958-1964; 2 folders (Box 11)
      - Banking and Currency, 1957-1964 (Box 11)
      - Bureau of the Budget, 1963 (Box 11)
      - Cancer, 1963 (Box 11)
      - Catholic Issues, 1963 (Box 11)
      - Census, 1959-1964 (Box 11)
      - Civil Defense, 1960-1963 (Box 11)
      - Civil Rights, 1952-1964; 7 folders (Box 11)
      - Civil Rights, 1952-1964; 4 folders (Box 12)
      - Civil Service General, 1956-1964 (Box 12)
      - Civil Service Retirement 16th District, 1956-1964 (Box 12)
      - Civil Service Investigation OTAC Detroit, 1956 (Box 12)
      - Civil Service Hatch Act, 1962 (Box 12)
      - Commerce Department, 1962 (Box 12)
      - Communications, 1959 (Box 12)
      - Communism, 1953-1962; 4 folders (Box 12)
      - Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1953-1954 (Box 12)
      - Counterfeiting, 1964 (Box 12)
      - Cuba, 1963 (Box 12)
      - Customs, 1963 (Box 12)
      - Department of Defense, 1956-1964 (Box 12)
      - Defense Contracts, 1959-1964 (Box 12)
      - Defense Department--Air Force, 1964 (Box 12)
      - Democratic Party, 1956 (Box 13)
      - Democratic National Committee, 1953-1962; 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Democratic National Convention, 1960-1964 (Box 13)
      - Democratic Study Group, 1960-1961 (Box 13)
      - Democratic Campaign, 1960 (Box 13)
      - Department of Interior, 1963 (Box 13)
      - Department of State, 1959-1960 (Box 13)
      - Department of Treasury, 1964 (Box 13)
      - Detergents, 1959-1963; 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Economics, 1960-1961 (Box 13)
      - Education School Construction, 1955-1964 (Box 13)
      - Employment, 1956-1964 (Box 13)
      - Fair Trade, 1962 (Box 13)
      - Farm Bill, 1964 (Box 13)
      - Federal Communications Commission, 1963-1964 (Box 13)
      - Federal Power, 1959-1964 (Box 13)
      - Federal Power Tennessee Valley Authority, 1959 (Box 13)
      - Federal Trade Commission, 1964 (Box 13)
      - Fluoridation, 1961 (Box 13)
      - Foreign Policy, 1956-1961 (Box 13)
      - Foreign Aid, 1964 (Box 13)
      - Foreign Aid Machine Tools, 1959-1964 (Box 13)
      - Foreign Claims, 1963-1964 (Box 13)
      - Foreign Trade Tariffs, 1955 (Box 13)
      - Foreign Trade, 1963 (Box 13)
      - Franking Privilege, 1955 (Box 13)
      - Gas Natural, 1952 (Box 14)
      - General Services Administration, 1963-1964 (Box 14)
      - Hawaiian Trip, 1959 (Box 14)
      - Health, 1960-1964; 4 folders (Box 14)
      - Health Bulletins, 1963-1964 (Box 14)
      - Holidays, undated (Box 14)
      - Hospitals, 1963 (Box 14)
      - Immigration, 1955-1963 (Box 14)
      - Inauguration, 1961 (Box 14)
      - Justice Department, 1955-1958 (Box 14)
      - Juvenile Delinquency, 1963 (Box 14)
      - Labor General, 1957-1963; 2 folders (Box 14)
      - Labor, Local 600, 1958-1960; 3 folders (Box 14)
      - Labor Organizations, 1961 (Box 14)
      - Labor-Walter Reuther, 1958 (Box 14)
      - Labor-Shorter Work-Week, 1957 (Box 14)
      - Legislation General, 1964 (Box 14)
      - Library of Congress, 1963-1964 (Box 14)
      - Liquor Commission, 1951-1954 (Box 14)
      - Lottery, 1959-1963 (Box 14)
      - Maritime Matters, 1960 (Box 14)
      - Medicare, 1962-1963 (Box 14)
      - Memorial Day, 1963 (Box 14)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1962 (Box 14)
      - National Confederation of American Ethnic Groups, 1964 (Box 14)
      - Nutrition, 1956-1958 (Box 14)
      - Old Aged and Aged, 1955 (Box 15)
      - Panama Canal, 1964 (Box 15)
      - Patents, 1958 (Box 15)
      - Patronage, 1956-1964; 13 folders (Box 15)
      - Polish Legions of American Veterans, 1959-1962 (Box 15)
      - Polish Museums, 1963 (Box 15)
      - Postal Organizations, 1960-1961 (Box 15)
      - Postal Service General, 1957-1964; 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Post Office and Civil Service Federal Employees Grievance Procedure, 1958 (Box 15)
      - Post Office and Civil Service Catholic Workers, 1959 (Box 15)
      - Post Office Construction, 1960 (Box 15)
      - Post Office Guideline Plan, 1960-1964 (Box 15)
      - Post Office Metro Plan, 1957 (Box 15)
      - Post Office Stamp Issues, 1956 (Box 15)
      - Post Office Stamp Campfire Girls, 1959 (Box 15)
      - Post Office Padrewski, 1960 (Box 15)
      - President meeting with, 1961 (Box 16)
      - Poverty, 1964 (Box 16)
      - Louis Rabaut Eulogies, 1962 (Box 16)
      - Religion Supreme Court Decisions, 1961-1962 (Box 16)
      - Requests for Flags, 1960 (Box 16)
      - Small Business, 1962-1963 (Box 16)
      - Social Security, 1955-1964 (Box 16)
      - Socialism, 1962 (Box 16)
      - Statehood Alaska and Hawaii, 1958 (Box 16)
      - Statehood Hawaii, 1959 (Box 16)
      - Statements Miscellaneous, 1961 (Box 16)
      - Surplus Property, 1964 (Box 16)
      - Taxes, 1958 (Box 16)
      - Taxes, 1964 (Box 16)
      - Taxation Banks, 1960-1961 (Box 16)
      - Un-American Activities Committee, 1955-1964 (Box 16)
      - "UFO Evidence" National Investigations Committee, 1964 (Box 16)
      - United Nations, 1963 (Box 16)
      - Urban Renewal, 1964 (Box 16)
      - Veterans, 1959-1964; 4 folders (Box 16)
      - Vice President, 1964 (Box 16)
      - Water, 1961 (Box 16)
      - Youth, 1961-1963 (Box 16)
    - Nationalities
      - Nationalities General, 1956-1964; 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Africa, 1961 (Box 16)
      - Captive Nations, 1956-1961 (Box 16)
      - Armenia, 1961-1964 (Box 16)
      - Bulgaria, 1961 (Box 16)
      - Byelorussia, 1963-1964 (Box 16)
      - China, 1961 (Box 16)
      - Italians, 1964 (Box 17)
      - Hungary, 1951-1963 (Box 17)
      - Latin America, 1961 (Box 17)
      - Latvia, 1957-1964 (Box 17)
      - Lithuania, 1958-1964 (Box 17)
      - Po, 1953-1964; 4 folders (Box 17)
      - Po, 1953-1964; 2 folders (Box 18)
      - Ukrainian, 1955-1964 (Box 18)
      - Ukrainian, Schevenko stamp, 1961 (Box 18)
      - Ukrainian, Taros Schevenko, 1963-1964 (Box 18)
  - Michigan Topical
    The Michigan files relate to general statewide topics, 16th District Towns/Post offices, 16th District General, and 16th District projects. Some of the prominent subjects include water pollution, the Detroit Wayne County Willow Run airport controversy, River Rouge development, and foreign trade issues in Michigan.
    - General
      - Air Pollution, 1963 (Box 19)
      - Area Redevelopment, 1963-1964 (Box 19)
      - Army Mobility Com, 1963-1964 (Box 19)
      - ATAC, 1961-1964; 4 folders (Box 19)
      - Benzie Air Base, 1955-1956; 3 folders (Box 19)
      - Contracts, 1961-1962; 2 folders (Box 19)
      - Democratic Congressional Delegation, 1958 (Box 19)
      - Defense Burroughs Corporation, 1962 (Box 19)
      - Detroit Arsenal, 1952-1954 (Box 19)
      - Detroit Edison, 1960-1964; 2 folders (Box 19)
      - Detroit Marina City, 1963 (Box 19)
      - Detroit Marine Terminals, 1962-1963 (Box 19)
      - Detroit Metropolitan Airport, 1962-1963 (Box 19)
      - Detroit Wayne County Willow Run Airport Controversy, 1955-1956; 4 folders (Box 20)
      - Detroit Olympic Committee, 1963 (Box 20)
      - Detroit Ordinance District, 1963 (Box 20)
      - Duo-Matic, 1960 (Box 20)
      - Economics, 1958-1964 (Box 20)
      - Education, 1964 (Box 20)
      - Flint Post Office, 1954-1956 (Box 20)
      - Henry Ford Stamp, 1961-1964; 2 folders (Box 20)
      - Foreign Trade Survey in Michigan, 1955-1964; 3 folders (Box 20)
      - Highways, 1959-1961 (Box 20)
      - History, 1958-1964 (Box 20)
      - Housing, 1961-1962 (Box 20)
      - Internal Revenue Service Center, 1961-1963 (Box 20)
      - Livonia Post Office, 1951-1952 (Box 20)
      - Miscellaneous, 1951-1964; 4 folders (Box 21)
      - NASA Electronics Center, 1964 (Box 21)
      - National Memorial Gardens, 1959-1964 (Box 21)
      - Politics, 1955-1961; 2 folders (Box 21)
      - Orchard Lake Post Office, 1962 (Box 21)
      - Petroleum Specialties, 1962-1964 (Box 21)
      - Port Development, 1961 (Box 21)
      - Port of Detroit, 1961-1963 (Box 21)
      - Post Office Christmas Employment, 1963 (Box 21)
      - Public Works, 1963-1964 (Box 21)
      - Reapportionment, 1961-1964; 2 folders (Box 21)
      - Senator Phil Hart, 1959-1964 (Box 22)
      - Senator Patrick McNamara, 1962-1964 (Box 22)
      - State Democratic Committee, 1955-1960; 3 folders (Box 22)
      - Water Pollution, 1951-1964; 3 folders (Box 22)
      - Wayne County, 1956-1959; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - 16th District post offices and local issues
      - Gross Isle, 1953-1964; 3 folders (Box 22)
      - Gross Isle Post Office, 1952-1953 (Box 22)
      - Huron Township, 1963-1964 (Box 22)
      - Inkster, 1955-1964 (Box 22)
      - Inkster Post Office, 1955-1964 (Box 22)
      - Lincoln Park, 1955-1964 (Box 22)
      - Lincoln Park Post Office, 1955-1964 (Box 22)
      - Melvindale, 1955-1964 (Box 22)
      - Melvindale Post Office, 1955-1964 (Box 22)
      - Nankin Township, 1961-1964 (Box 22)
      - Nankin Township Post Office, 1961-1964 (Box 23)
      - New Boston Post Office, 1955-1964 (Box 23)
      - Newayne, 1955-1964; 3 folders (Box 23)
      - River Rouge, 1955-1964; 3 folders (Box 23)
      - Riverview, 1963 (Box 23)
      - Riverview Urban Renewal, 1963 (Box 23)
      - Riverview Post Office, 1956-1963 (Box 23)
      - Rockwood, 1961-1964 (Box 23)
      - Rockwood Post Office, 1956-1964 (Box 23)
      - Romulus, 1960-1964 (Box 23)
      - Romulus Urban Renewal, 1963-1964 (Box 23)
      - Romulus Post Office, 1951-1964 (Box 23)
      - Southgate, 1961-1964 (Box 23)
      - Southgate Post Office, 1961-1964 (Box 23)
      - Sumpter Township, 1963-1964 (Box 23)
      - Taylor, 1961-1964 (Box 23)
      - Taylor Post Office, 1952-1962 (Box 23)
      - Trenton, 1959-1964 (Box 23)
      - Trenton Post Office, 1955-1963 (Box 23)
      - Van Buren Township, 1963-1964 (Box 23)
      - Wayne, 1960-1964 (Box 23)
      - Wayne Post Office, 1952-1964 (Box 23)
      - Wayne Urban Renewal, 1956-1964 (Box 23)
      - Woodhaven, 1961-1964 (Box 24)
      - Wyandotte Post Office, 1953-1964 (Box 24)
      - Wyandotte Urban Renewal, 1962-1964 (Box 24)
      - Wyandotte, 1959-1964 (Box 24)
      - West, 1964 (Box 24)
      - Subseries 16th District General (Box 24)
    - 16th District General, 1955-1964; 3 folders
      - 16th District History, 1953 (Box 24)
      - Housing, 1956-1958 (Box 24)
      - John Lesinski Club, 1959-1964 (Box 24)
      - Politics, 1961-1964; 2 folders (Box 24)
      - Postmasters, 1959 (Box 24)
      - Public Works, 1961-1963 (Box 24)
      - Race Track Passes, 1955-1956 (Box 24)
      - Schools, 1953-1954 (Box 24)
    - 16th District Projects
      - General, 1957-1962 (Box 24)
      - Baby Creek Sewer, 1956-1961 (Box 24)
      - Central Wayne County Sanitation Authority, 1962 (Box 24)
      - Ecorse Mud Is, 1961-1964 (Box 24)
      - Fort Wayne, 1962-1963 (Box 24)
      - Huron River Watershed, 1961-1963 (Box 24)
      - Huron River, 1961-1964 (Box 24)
      - Melvindale Ordnance Plant, 1955-1959 (Box 25)
      - Olympic Rowing Course, 1961-1963 (Box 25)
      - Romulus Plant, 1961-1962 (Box 25)
      - Rouge River Channel, 1950-1964; 7 folders; 1 oversize folders (Box 25)
      - Wayne County Sexton-Kilfoil Drain, 1962-1964 (Box 25)
      - Telegraph Road, 1962-1963 (Box 25)
      - Trenton Channel, 1962-1964; 2 folders (Box 25)
      - Trenton Channel, 1958-1963 (Box 26)
      - Trenton Channel Army Engineers, 1955-1964 (Box 26)
      - Trenton Channel Resolutions in Favor, 1961-1962 (Box 26)
      - Wayne County Road Commission, 1962-1964 (Box 26)
  - Case Files
    Although a congressman must deal with a myriad of constituent problems, matters of unemployment, social security, admission to the service academies, Lesinski, because of the demography of his district, was heavily involved in matters of immigration with his Polish American and Arab American constituents. These case files include bills passed in relief of immigrants seeking asylum and naturalization, correspondence with individuals, and other files related to the cases. These files are especially important in light of Lesinski's work with the Polish-American community.
    - Bartolo Alcantar, 1963 (Box 26)
    - Yasuko Agena, 1963 (Box 26)
    - Andrew Androvic (Box 26)
    - Ilona Astalos, 1963 (Box 26)
    - Miklos Balogh, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Julianna Banda, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Dorin Baron, 1956 (Box 26)
    - Marija Barsi, 1956 (Box 26)
    - Lottie Barwinski, 1962 (Box 26)
    - Daniel Baryski, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Dorothy Baskin, 1960 (Box 26)
    - John Batyik, 1962 (Box 26)
    - Teofila Bernecki, 1963 (Box 26)
    - Helena Bilinska, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Joseph Bisnaire, 1953 (Box 26)
    - Czelaw Bochenski, 1963 (Box 26)
    - Zeldi Bornstayn, 1962 (Box 26)
    - Guisepe Bossio, 1956 (Box 26)
    - Gordon Bozanich, 1958 (Box 26)
    - Dante Ciatti, 1961 (Box 26)
    - Vitold Cieplinski, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Gio Cracchiolo, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Francisc Csiszar, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Helen Czadankiewicz, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Stella Czarnecki, 1964 (Box 26)
    - D, 1957 (Box 26)
    - Louis Dabrowski, 1962 (Box 26)
    - Mohamad Hassan Dardari, 1958 (Box 26)
    - Armenouhi Eghiazarian, 1963 (Box 26)
    - Alie Mohammed El Hajj, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Anthanosios Gianoupolos, 1963 (Box 26)
    - Alexandra Gromak, 1962 (Box 26)
    - Waldemar Gronowsky, 1962 (Box 26)
    - Anastasia Hnatiw, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Nicholas Holowka, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Bela and Sandor Huszti, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Jovan and Vesa Iljevski, 1962 (Box 26)
    - Carmel Isola, 1962 (Box 26)
    - Monika Itryna, 1961 (Box 26)
    - Stanislaw Jagutka, 1960 (Box 26)
    - Aniela Jakubiec, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Francis Jarecki, 1953 (Box 26)
    - Manuel Kallabat, 1961 (Box 26)
    - Manuel Kassab, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Alyas Kassab, 1960 (Box 26)
    - Aglaia Kastoras, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Wali Khan, 1956 (Box 26)
    - Imre Kiss, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Miodrag Kitanovich, 1958 (Box 26)
    - Jack Kocsis, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Felix Kolodoziej, 1962 (Box 26)
    - Joseph Komarski, 1955 (Box 26)
    - Roy Komraus, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Apolline Kossakowski, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Dioysios Kotinis, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Bessie Kour, 1961 (Box 26)
    - Chester Kozdroj, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Genawefa Kozub, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Kyriakos Kyriakou, 1963 (Box 27)
    - Henry Laskowski, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Jozefa Lewandowska, 1962 (Box 27)
    - Lottie Lewandowska, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Joseph Lieb, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Angelo Lovechhio, 1960 (Box 27)
    - Sophie Malinowski, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Daniel Milkovich, 1963 (Box 27)
    - Yousif Najjar, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Thaddeus Nowak, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Wereonika Plawecki, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Joseph Rosiak, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Hayman Rubenstien, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Enrique Saralegui, 1964 (Box 27)
    - John Sakellaris, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Joseph Wegrecki, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Barbara Wojtusiak, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Patricia Van Eck, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Mrs. Samuel Van Til, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Bishop Valerian, 1963 (Box 27)
    - Gaspari Vitale, 1953 (Box 27)
    - Tomaso Vitale, 1951 (Box 27)
    - Louis Vogle, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Miluten and Vladimir Vunic, 1961 (Box 27)
    - Zygmunt Zakrzewski, 1962 (Box 27)
    - Mrs. Martin Zbosnik, 1962 (Box 27)
    - Joseph Zdanowski, 1962 (Box 27)
    - Margherita Zebri, 1959 (Box 27)
    - Vilma Zelenak, 1963 (Box 27)
    - Franceso Zoli, 1960 (Box 27)
- Biographical / Personal
  The Biographical / Personal series includes some personal correspondence, scrapbooks and clippings from his congressional service, and awards and certificates.
  - Biographical Information (Box 27)
    (include information regarding John Lesinski, Sr.)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1960-1962; 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Awards and certificates (Box 27)
  - Clippings (Box 27)
  - Scrapbooks
    - 1950-1960 (Volume 1)
    - 1960-1963 (Volume 2)
    - 1963-1964 (Volume 3)
- Visual materials
  The Visual Materials series consists of portraits and photographs from Lesinski's Congressional career, including campaign events and group photos of Lesinski with other public figures, including John F. Kennedy, Lyndon Baines Johnson, Sam Rayburn, John McCormack, and Gerald R. Ford. The series also contains earlier photographs of John Lesinski, Sr. and exterior views of the Hamtramck Lumber & Supply Company. Also part of this series are a few motion pictures and a CD-ROM of older photographs of family members.
  - Photographs
    - Portraits (Box 27)
    - Lesinski in US Navy during World War II (Box 27)
    - Lesinski with John F. Kennedy and Lyndon B. Johnson, and other political figures (Box 27)
      (see also autographed portraits of Dwight Eisenhower and Murray D. Van Wagoner in oversize folder UAm)
    - Lesinski with Congressional leaders and colleagues (Box 27)
      (include photos with Sam Rayburn, John McCormack)
    - Lesinski with Michigan political figures (Box 27)
      (include Blair Moody, G. Mennen Williams, Gerald R. Ford)
    - Lesinski participating in Congressional committee work (Box 27)
    - Political events (Box 27)
    - Social events (Box 27)
    - Look Magazine article photos featuring Lesinski and related correspondence (Box 27)
    - Lesinski and family members (Box 27)
    - Lesinski as part of miscellaneous, largely unidentified groups, 4 folders (Box 27)
    - US Navy and Army related meetings and events (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 27)
    - John Lesinski, Sr. (Box 27)
      (see also oversize folder, UAm)
    - Hamtramck Lumber Company photos, 1930s; 4 folders (Box 27)
  - Photographs of "Leskinski's grandparents", 1 optical disks CD-Rs (Box 27)
    three scans on CD. (full names not given)